export const PICTUREMAKINGA2019 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The caveman made art to",
A: "beautify his dwelling place.",
B: "improve his skills in art.",
C: "meet his basic needs.",
D: "ward off his enemies.",
answer: "C. meet his basic needs.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. A painting technique of contrasting light and dark tones is termed",
A: "chiaroscuro.",
B: "sfumato.",
C: "shading.",
D: "tinting,",
answer: "A. chiaroscuro.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. The profile of a drawn human is the",
A: "back view.",
B: "front view.",
C: "full view.",
D: "side view.",
answer: "D. side view.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Colour which is free from any admixture is termed",
A: "chroma.",
B: "neutral.",
C: "shade.",
D: "tint.",
answer: "A. chroma.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. In Ghanaian colour symbolism, blue signifies",
A: "old age.",
B: "peace,",
C: "prosperity.",
D: "war.",
answer: "B. peace.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. When a colour scheme comprise of a hue and it’s values, it is said to be",
A: "dichromatic.",
B: "monochromatic.",
C: "polychromatic.",
D: "trichromatic.",
answer: "B. monochromatic.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Which of these options will give the strongest contrast?",
A: "Analogous colours",
B: "Complementary colours",
C: "Secondary colours",
D: "Tertiary colours",
answer: "B. Complementary colours",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. A twelve-point colour wheel consist of",
A: "one set of triadic colours.",
B: "two scts of triadic colours.",
C: "three sets of triadic colours.",
D: "four sets of triadic colours,",
answer: "C. three sets of triadic colours.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. The function ofa vehicle in paint is to",
A: "bind smaller particles of pigment.",
B: "carry pigment to where it is needed.",
C: "dissolve the pigment to prevent hardening.",
D: "loosen the pigment for easy application.",
answer: "A. bind smaller particles of pigment.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Choose the main support for tempera painting from the options.",
A: "Canvas",
B: "Gesso",
C: "Panel",
D: "Straw board",
answer: "C. Panel",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Pastel drawings are preserved by",
A: "fixing.",
B: "lacquering.",
C: "stretching,",
D: "varnishing,",
answer: "A. fixing.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. Canvas is primed before painting so that, the",
A: "design will be seen.",
B: "pores will be sealed.",
C: "work will be matty.",
D: "work will look bright.",
answer: "B. pores will be sealed.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. The painting medium that has egg yolk as a binder is",
A: "acrylic.",
B: "poster colour.",
C: "tempera.",
D: "watercolour,",
answer: "C. tempera.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. The appearance of an object is described as the",
A: "contour.",
B: "shape.",
C: "silhouette.",
D: "size.",
answer: "B. shape.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. Pigments are mixed with wax to produce",
A: "acrylic.",
B: "crayons.",
C: "pastels.",
D: "tempera.",
answer: "B. crayons.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. The visual expression of beauty is referred to as",
A: "aesthetics.",
B: "appreciation.",
C: "art.",
D: "design.",
answer: "A. aesthetics.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. A composition is said to be good when the ‘",
A: "bigger objects are emphasized.",
B: "drawing is made by a popular artist.",
C: "drawing is painted in monochrome.",
D: "positive and negative areas balance.",
answer: "D. positive and negative areas balance.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. Which of these options creates a feeling of stability in a painting?",
A: "Balance",
B: "Dominance",
C: "Proportion",
D: "Rhythm",
answer: "A. Balance",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Once characteristic of a creative artist is",
A: "anxiety.",
B: "aggression.",
C: "curiosity.",
D: "imitation.",
answer: "C. curiosity.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. The intention of perspective is to create",
A: "centre of interest.",
B: "distance and depth.",
C: "height and weight.",
D: "paralle! lines.",
answer: "B. distance and depth.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Identify a form from the following options.",
A: "Circle",
B: "Cube",
C: "Octagon",
D: "Square",
answer: "B. Cube",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. In tona! gradation, intense colours placed beside pale colours tend to",
A: "advance.",
B: "bleed.",
C: "blur.",
D: "recede.",
answer: "A. advance.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Which of the following options is primarily used in sizing canvas?",
A: "Glue",
B: "Lacquer",
C: "Thinner",
D: "Wax",
answer: "A. Glue",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. In serigraphy, masking tapes are fastened to the corners of screens to",
A: "allow dyes to settle.",
B: "allow squeegee to move fast.",
C: "prevent printing ink from seeping.",
D: "strengthen the edges of the screen.",
answer: "C. prevent printing ink from seeping.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. A painter using poster colours can obtain shades of grey by mixing",
A: "all the rainbow colours.",
B: "black colour with water.",
C: "black with white colours.",
D: "two primary colours.",
answer: "C. black with white colours.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Which of the following techniques involve burning?",
A: "Engraving,",
B: "Etching",
C: "Pyrography",
D: "Serigraphy",
answer: "C. Pyrography",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Select the pair of techniques which involve both assembling and pasting.",
A: "Marquetry and fresco",
B: "Marquetry and mosaic",
C: "Mosaic and painting",
D: "Painting and fresco",
answer: "B. Marquetry and mosaic",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. The aesthetic importance of making collage is",
A: "decoration.",
B: "entertainment.",
C: "preservation.",
D: "sales",
answer: "A. decoration.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Drawing from a model enables the artist to",
A: "build self confidence.",
B: "imagine the human body.",
C: "represent the figures in action.",
D: "study the human anatomy.",
answer: "D. study the human anatomy.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Which of the following statements is true about drawing?",
A: "All drawings have perspective.",
B: "An eraser is indispensable.",
C: "drawings begin with sketches.",
D: "The best position for drawing is to stand.",
answer: "C. drawings begin with sketches.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. A drawn figure is proportional when",
A: "lines are neatly outlined.",
B: "parts are properly related.",
C: "spaces are utilized well.",
D: "tones are applied all over.",
answer: "B. parts are properly related.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. The highlight on an object suggests the",
A: "artist’s position.",
B: "colours used.",
C: "source of light.",
D: "technique used.",
answer: "C. source of light.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. The merging of tones without clear demarcation is referred to as",
A: "alla prima.",
B: "chiaroscuro,",
C: "sfumato.",
D: "sgraffito.",
answer: "C. sfumato.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Identify the relationship between yellow and a mixture of red and blue on the twelve-point colour wheel. They are",
A: "adjacent.",
B: "complementary.",
C: "primary.",
D: "tertiary.",
answer: "B. complementary.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Achromatic colours are regarded as neutral because they",
A: "only modify hues to different tones.",
B: "produce a new hue when mixed,",
C: "result in black when mixed together.",
D: "turn brown when mixed with other colours.",
answer: "A. only modify hues to different tones.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Which of the following options best explains the term focal colour?",
A: "Actual colours of objects",
B: "Colours imagined by artists",
C: "Locally manufactured colours",
D: "Reflected colours in the environment",
answer: "A. Actual colours of objects",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Select the theme adopted by the impressionists to execute their work.",
A: "Anatomy",
B: "Plein air",
C: "Portraiture",
D: "Still life",
answer: "B. Plein air",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. In computer graphics, which of the following is a vector imaging application?",
A: "Adobe photoshop",
B: "Coral draw",
C: "Coral photopaint",
D: "Paint box",
answer: "B. Coral draw",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Select from the options, the statement that best describes acrylic paint. It",
A: "does not blend easily.",
B: "does not mix well with water.",
C: "is difficult to work with.",
D: "is quick drying.",
answer: "D. is quick drying.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Crimson, scarlet and vermillion are all",
A: "cool colours.",
B: "hot colours.",
C: "tetradic colours.",
D: "triadic colours.",
answer: "B. hot colours.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},


]